

1974-1975

1974-1975

ANTONIO CARLOS MARCATO

Antonio Carlos Marcato is the founding partner of Marcato Advogados, a boutique law firm specialized in civil litigation and insurance law.

In more than 30 years of practice, has served as a Justice in the Appellate Court of the State of São Paulo, as Public Prosecutor at the Attorney General's Office of the State of São Paulo, and as arbitrator in a number of commercial proceedings.

Is a associate professor at the Universidade de São Paulo (USP) and a visiting professor at several other institutions. He has published more than a dozen books, hundreds of articles, and is a speaker at National and International institutions.

Recently served as a special advisor to the General Committee rapporteur constituted by Brazilian Magistrate Association (AMB), advising on the drafting and inception of new civil procedure code in the House of Representatives.

DATA:

Adress: Al. Santos, 234, 8º andar, Cerqueira César, Cep. 01418-000

Phone: (55 11) 3437.8600

E-mail: marcato@marcatoadv.com.br

EXPERIENCE

MARCATO ADVOGADOS LAW FIRM Founding Partner	2000-present
UNIVERSIDADE DE SÃO PAULO (USP) Associate Professor	1998-present
APPELLATE COURT OF THE STATE OF SÃO PAULO Justice	1990-2000
ATTORNEY GENERAL'S OFFICE OF THE STATE OF SÃO PAULO Public Prosecutor	1975-1990

ARBITRAL EXPERIENCE: Act as arbitrator since 2002 in several Arbitration Chambers

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDADE DE SAO PAULO (US

Postgraduate in Civil Procedure

Postgraduate in Constitutional Law

1987-1989
1980-1984
1969-1973
197 <u>4-</u> 1975

TEL (55 11) 3437.8600 - FAX (55 11) 3437.8601 - MARCATO@MARCATOADV.COM.BR



PROFESSIONAL LANGUAGES: Portuguese and Spanish

MEMBERSHIPS AND AFFILIATIONS

- Admitted to the Brazilian Bar Association, São Paulo (No. 33.412)
- Member of the Insurance Law Committee of the São Paulo Bar Association (OAB-SP)
- Member of the legal counsel for the Federation of Industries of the State of São Paulo (CONJUR FIESP)
- Member and Counselor of the Mediation and Arbitration Chamber of the Confederation of Industries of the State of São Paulo (CIESP)
- Member of the International Association of Civil Law
- Member of the Iberoamerican Association of Procedural Law
- Member of the Brazilian Institute of Procedure Law
- Listed as arbitrator of CAM-FIESP, CAESP, and CAM-FIEP

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Procedimentos Especiais. 16. ed. São Paulo: Atlas, 2016.
- Código de Processo Civil Interpretado. 3. ed. São Paulo: Atlas, 2006.
- O Processo Monitório Brasileiro. 2. ed. São Paulo: Malheiros, 2000.
- Ação de Consignação em Pagamento. 5. ed. São Paulo: Malheiros, 1996.